### **Daniel Ahn**

Fort Lee, NJ (917) 733 - 5236 93danielahn@gmail.com Portfolio LinkedIn Github

Full stack software engineer with 7 years of experience in sales, management, customer service, and operations. With a background in the hospitality industry, I bring the necessary soft skills to work in a collaborative environment, especially in pair programming. I enjoy creating dynamic web applications by writing clean, readable code. Experienced in Ruby and JavaScript frameworks.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: JavaScript, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL Frameworks/Libraries: React, Redux, Ruby on Rails Database Management: PostgreSQL, SQLite Other: Git, GitHub, Webpack, Semantic UI

## Technical Projects

#### Wednesday - GitHub (Frontend) | GitHub (Backend) | Live Site

<u>Collaboration and chatting application based on Slack</u>

- Created a Rails API backend to control database management and utilized React, Redux, and React Router to control frontend and user experience.
- Enabled user authorization and authentication with JSON Web Tokens and local storage
- Implemented Websockets via ActionCable to enable real time chat between users
- Applied Semantic React UI and custom CSS for styling

#### **GrumpyBird** - GitHub | Live Site

Flappy Bird inspired clone created with HTML, Javascript, and Canvas

- Created game structure and gameplay with Vanilla JavaScript and Object Oriented Programming
- Utilized Webpack to load JavaScript and bundle scripts
- Rendered components (bird, background, pipes) using HTML5 Canvas
- Created collision detection algorithm between bird and pipe to account for scores and game over

# Professional Experience

#### Lenwich, New York, NY

09/2016 - 06/2019

Senior Catering Sales Coordinator

- Monitored daily catering operations for 18 locations, supervised 30+ general managers, and sustained yearly catering sales of \$3M+
- Generated cold call leads and exceeded monthly catering sales by 10%
- Attained the largest sale in company history (\$100K+), which resulted in a 10% increase in sales.

#### Lenwich, New York, NY

01/2012 - 09/2016

General Manager Candidate, Shift Supervisor

- Supervised and trained a staff of 20+ per shift for top location with weekly sales of \$70K+
- Mentored staff on best customer service practices, increasing sales by 7%
- Developed daily sales reports to send to headquarter

#### Weiss-Rohlig, Cranford, NJ

10/2015 - 01/2016

**Operations Intern** 

- Assisted the key accounts department with sales totaling to 1/3 of the branch
- Managed air and sea customs clearance process
- Tracked and monitored key accounts shipments

#### **Education**

### Flatiron School, New York, NY

08/2019 - 11/2019

**Software Engineering Immersive** 

## **Rutgers Business School**, New Brunswick, NJ Bachelor of Science in Supply Chain Management

09/2012 - 11/2016